<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Db on Alex Pliutau</title>
    <link>/tags/db/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Db on Alex Pliutau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alex Pliutau</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 13:27:00 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/db/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with DB datetime/date columns in Go</title>
      <link>/working-with-db-time-in-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 May 2017 13:27:00 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-with-db-time-in-go/</guid>
      <description>This post shows how to work with DATETIME/DATE columns in DB and use Go standard time.Time avoiding manual string parsing. This article contains examples using 2 packages: database/sql and github.com/go-sql-driver/mysql.
Retrieve nullable time field using NullTime type MySQL, PostgreSQL drivers in Go provide this nullable type which represents a time.Time that may be NULL. NullTime implements the Scanner interface so it can be used as a scan destination:
 Use parseTime=true Assuming you&amp;rsquo;re using the go-sql-driver/mysql you can ask the driver to scan DATE and DATETIME automatically to time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with DB nulls in Golang</title>
      <link>/working-with-db-nulls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Apr 2016 09:17:49 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/working-with-db-nulls/</guid>
      <description>This post shows how to marshall NULL values from the database into Go struct and how to avoid mistakes during fetching optional values with SELECT query. I&amp;rsquo;ll show standard types sql.NullString, sql.NullInt64, etc types.
Customer table example Customer table has mandatory ID and Email fields and optional Phone(string)/Age(int). I will show you a basic code how to fetch Customer by Email, marshall data into Go struct.
 Error Now let&amp;rsquo;s imagine that our Customer has an empty Phone (NULL in the DB), in this case SQL driver will fail to marshall DB NULL into string with the following error:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>