<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Git on Alex Pliutau</title>
    <link>/tags/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Git on Alex Pliutau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alex Pliutau</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 23:09:17 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>o means open. Simple CLI tool to open repository in browser.</title>
      <link>/o_simple_cli_to_open_repo_in_browser/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Aug 2017 23:09:17 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/o_simple_cli_to_open_repo_in_browser/</guid>
      <description>Here is my small bash function! When you run it from the terminal it opens the GitHub/BitBucket/GitLab page in your browser for the git repository you are currently in. It has a short simple name o. I find myself doing this quite a lot as I am working with multiple repositories at the same time and switching to a browser, searching for correct link, etc.
Just type o :)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Garbage Collection in Git</title>
      <link>/git-gc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jul 2017 15:48:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/git-gc/</guid>
      <description>To understand git garbage collector, we need to understand how branches work. Branches are just pointers to commits that move whenever a new commit is created.
Any time you do git commit --amend or git rebase a new commit object is created. But what happens to the old one? Old commit objects stick around in the datastore. The reason you don’t see them is because there are no pointers to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using different Git emails</title>
      <link>/using-different-git-emails/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Jul 2017 22:28:23 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/using-different-git-emails/</guid>
      <description>Usually at work and at home we use different Git name/email pairs, or even per project. Pushing with correct email guarantees that your commits will be authored with a correct user identity.
This configuration stored in .gitconfig file and looks like:
[user] name = Alex Pliutau email = home@example.com  Git 2.13 introduces conditional configuration includes. For now, the only supported condition is matching the filesystem path of the repository, but that&amp;rsquo;s exactly what we need in this case.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Useful Git global config and ignore rules</title>
      <link>/useful-global-git-config-and-ignore-rules/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Apr 2017 10:47:24 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/useful-global-git-config-and-ignore-rules/</guid>
      <description>I am working with git every single day, from different machines and accounts. And all these hosts have the same global git configuration. I sync it using tiny bash script.
~/.gitconfig I have user-specific configuration located in ~/.gitconfig, you can check it here.
Common exclude rules, ignoring temporary files, IDE files, logs, binary files, etc. You don&amp;rsquo;t want to see them in repository, right?
[core] excludesfile = ~/.gitignore  Shortcuts for git clone:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>gh: a tiny tool to manage GitHub repositories in your GOPATH</title>
      <link>/gh_in_gopath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Mar 2017 15:54:14 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gh_in_gopath/</guid>
      <description>As a Golang developer I have to clone a lot of packages/tools/etc into $GOPATH/src/github.com. Sometimes I do go get, sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s necessary to do a combination of mkdir + git clone. So to save my time I wrote a tiny function gh, that actually is the same as cd thatbut also can close repo if it doesn&amp;rsquo;t exist.
 Here it is, just add it to your ~/.bashrc:
gh() { if [[ $# -ne 2 ]]; then echo &amp;quot;USAGE: gh [user] [repo]&amp;quot; return fi GOPATH=${GOPATH:-$HOME/go} user_path=$GOPATH/src/github.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>