<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wizeline on Alex Pliutau</title>
    <link>/tags/wizeline/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wizeline on Alex Pliutau</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Alex Pliutau</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 09:21:50 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/wizeline/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning from Engineer to Engineering Manager</title>
      <link>/transitioning-from-eng-to-em/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 May 2018 09:21:50 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/transitioning-from-eng-to-em/</guid>
      <description>A couple of months ago I moved from a Team Lead position to being an engineering manager at Wizeline Vietnam on a small sized team. I&amp;rsquo;ve found that this role change come with a mindset change. Some things that mattered before when I was an individual contributor (writing good code, applying best engineering practices) became less important. On the other hand, new things became more important, e.g. team health, team success and team career growth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Coming soon: Microservices with Go Workshop, Vietnam, HCMC</title>
      <link>/microservices-with-go-workshop-vetnam/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Nov 2017 15:30:11 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/microservices-with-go-workshop-vetnam/</guid>
      <description>One month ago Wizline organized the Microservices with Go Workshop in Mexico, GDL as part of Wizeline Academy
I am happy to announce that we&amp;rsquo;re opening Wizeline Academy now in Vietnam, HCMC. And we will do similar workshop here, don&amp;rsquo;t miss it.
 Date: December 9 FB Page Event Page  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wizeline Academy: Microservices with Go</title>
      <link>/wizeline-academy-microservices-with-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2017 00:29:24 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/wizeline-academy-microservices-with-go/</guid>
      <description>What I like about Wizeline is that we have an amazing Academy, both internal and public. Yesterday I was in Mexico, Guadalajara office of Wizeline and I was doing a workshop about Microservices with Go.
The idea was to tell people about SOA approach, gRPC, Protocol Buffers and code a fictional application based on these principles in Go.
I am happy with results, especially when I saw how talented people are, even with new language for them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Games based on Voice Recognition</title>
      <link>/voice-recognition-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Jul 2017 14:50:34 +0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/voice-recognition-games/</guid>
      <description>Hi, folks!
Last Saturday I was very inspired by Alexa skills using server-side Swift talk organized by Wizeline Vietnam team. Speakers made a demo of how can we use Alex Skill in League of Legends (LoL). This Skill enables a user to retrieve the statistics of the enemy team mid-match using voice-enabled commands.
I went home with an idea of building a game, fully based on voice recognition, without any interface.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>